A Guide to the Berry Family Papers, 1803-1864
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Berry Family Papers, 1803-1864
The Library of Virginia
22120c
127 pages
Berry Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from C. J. Carrier of Bridgewater, Virginia, 28 April 1943.
Biographical Information
Robert Taylor Berry was born 6 July 1812 at Berry Plain in King George County, Virginia. He became a minister and married Ann Frame Griggs (10 August 1817-26 August 185?). They had at least two sons. Robert Berry served a church located in Georgetown in the District of Columbia. He died 2 November 1887 in Winchester, Virginia. Robert and Ann Berry are buried in Edge Hill cemetery in Charles Town, Jefferson County, West Virginia. Eliza M. Griggs (1794-1859), the mother of Ann Berry, lived in Charles Town. Katherine H. Bedinger (d. 1866) is Reverend Berry's sister. Jane Rebecca (1826-1894), Virginia Keightley (1826-1894), and Frances Massa Griggs (1822-1895) were sisters of Ann Berry.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1803-1864, of the Berry family of Charles Town, Jefferson County, (West) Virginia and Georgetown, District of Columbia, consisting mainly of personal and business correspondence to and from Ann Frame Berry (1817-185?) and Robert Taylor Berry (1812-1887). Also includes accounts, invitations, notes, powers of attorney, and tickets.
Contents List
- Letter, 18 November 1803, from Alexander St. Clair, Staunton, Virginia, to the executors of Colonel George Nicholas, Lexington, Kentucky, concerning a land deal between him and Nicholas some years previous.
- Power of attorney, 14 April 1815, from John Smith, Albemarle County, Virginia, to William Patrick, Augusta County, Virginia.
- Account, 1814-1816, William Patrick with James Johnston.
- Account, March-August 1833, Charles Patrick with Brooks and Stuart.
- Account, August-December 1833, Charles Patrick with Brooks and Stuart.
- Letter, 22 March 1839, from S.T. and another student at the University of Virginia to Eliza Griggs, Charles Town, (West) Virginia, sending greetings to friends back in Jefferson County, (West) Virginia, asking that condolences be forwarded concerning the death of a friend, and commenting on life at the University.
- Letter, 12 June 1839, from Jane R. Griggs and Eliza Griggs, Charles Town, to Anne F. Berry, their sister and daughter, Warren County, Virginia, sending family and social news.
- Letter, 14 September 1839, from Robert T. Berry, Georgetown, D.C., to his wife Anne F. Berry, Charles Town, describing his trip and preaching. He also mentions a "catastrophe" waiting to happen to her. This may have been the birth of their son Lee, who was born about this time.
- Letter, 15 September 1839, from Robert T. Berry, Georgetown, to Anne F. Berry, Charles Town, stating that he is glad that he received a letter from her and that the "catastrophe" was not too bad. He adds that he is changing his schedule to be with Anne for a few days.
- Letter, 5 November 1839, from Anne F. Berry, Charles Town, to Robert T. Berry, Georgetown, commenting on taking furniture from Charles Town, discussing their son Lee, and stating she misses Robert.
- Letter, 4 January 1840, from Eliza Griggs, Charles Town, to her daughter Anne F. Berry, Georgetown, sending family and personal news, and discussing the hiring out of slaves.
- Letter, 8 April 1840, from M. W. Berry, Fredericksburg, Virginia, to Robert T. Berry, Georgetown, concerning the illness of a relative and other family and social news, as well as the health of Robert and Anne Berry.
- Letter, 3 June 1840, from Katherine H. Bediger, Shepherdstown, (West) Virginia, to Robert T. Berry, Georgetown, concerning money she is sending him, her mental health, and news of their family which is not good.
- Letter, 17 May 1841, from Mary [?] to Robert T. Berry, Georgetown, concerning religion and social news.
- Letter, 21 May 1841, from Anne F. Berry, Georgetown, to Robert T. Berry, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, providing news of her and their son, stating that they miss him, and other family news.
- Letter, 16 June 1841, from Frances Massa Griggs, Charles Town, to Anne F. Berry, Georgetown, sending family and local news.
- Letter, September 1842, from Robert T. Berry, Georgetown, to Anne F. Berry, Charles Town, discussing their separation and stating he misses her, but that she should stay as long as she wants in Charles Town during the end of her pregnancy.
- Letter, 10 October 1842, from Robert T. Berry, Georgetown, to Anne F. Berry, Charles Town, commenting on his trip on church business and sending other social news.
- Letter, 21 October 1842, from Laura Berry, Alexandria, Virginia, to Anne F. Berry, Charles Town, apologizing for being a poor correspondent, informing her of the death of a young relative, congratulating Anne on her delivery, and other Berry family news.
- Note, 31 December 1842, from the ladies of the Bible class at the Georgetown Presbyterian Church to Robert T. Berry, giving a new year's offering as a token of their affection.
- Letter, 8 March and 15 March 1843, from Jane R. Griggs, Georgetown, to Eliza M. Griggs, Charles Town, concerning her visit with her sister Anne F. Berry and family, as well as other personal and social news.
- Letter, 11 December 1843, from [Jane R. Griggs], Georgetown, to Eliza M. Griggs, Charles Town, discussing a visit to the Berrys in Georgetown and social news.
- Letter, 9 June 1844, from Robert T. Berry, Georgetown, to Anne F. Berry, Charles Town, describing his trip home and sending news.
- Letter, 17 June 1844, from Robert T. Berry, Georgetown, to Anne F. Berry, Charles Town, concerning his health, his preaching, and social and religious matters.
- Letter, 29 June 1844, from Anne F. Berry, Jefferson County, (West) Virginia, to Robert T. Berry, Georgetown, concerning their children, her and the children's stay in Charles Town, the possibility of another child, and family and social news.
- Letter, 20 August 1844, from Robert T. Berry, Georgetown, to Anne F. Berry, Charles Town, discussing the weather, his preaching, and other social and personal news.
- Letter, 17 September 1845, from Anne F. Berry, Georgetown, to Eliza M. Griggs, Charles Town, concerning the anniversary of Anne's father's death, personal and family news.
- Letter, 4 May 1846, from Anne T. Berry, Georgetown, to Virginia and Frances Griggs, Charles Town, sending family and personal news.
- Invitation, 15 July 1846, from G. W. Sappington, et. al., to the Misses Griggs inviting them to a cotillion party on 22 July.
- Letter, 12 October 1847, from Virginia and Frances Griggs, Charles Town, to Anne F. Berry, Georgetown, concerning Anne's son who is visiting his aunts and other family and social news.
- Letter, 13 June 1848, from Anne F. Berry, Georgetown, to Eliza M. Griggs, Charles Town, concerning her son's health and his hope to visit his grandmother, along with other personal, social, and family news.
- Letter, 21 August 1848, from Anne F. Berry, Charles Town, to Robert T. Berry, Georgetown, asking about his trip home, and describing her visit with her family.
- Letter, October 1848, from M. W. Berry, Alexandria, to Robert T. Berry, Georgetown, sending a letter, commenting on going to the Virginia synod, and other personal news.
- Letter, 11 December 1848, from Robert T. Berry, Georgetown, to Eliza M. Griggs, Charles Town, informing her how he and the family are doing.
- Letter, 10 September 1849, from Anne F. Berry, Charles Town, to Robert T. Berry, Martinsburg, (West) Virginia, concerning the health of their son Frank.
- Letter, 19 July 1852, from M. W. Berry, Fredericksburg, to Robert T. Berry, Georgetown, concerning his visit to Georgetown and Alexandria and hoping that he and his family will attend a family reunion.
- Letter, 26 December 1852, from Jane Rebecca Griggs, Charles Town, to Eliza M. Griggs, Martinsburg, sending news and commenting on the birth of a son to Anne F. Berry.
- Letter, 10 January 1854, from Frances Massa Griggs, Charles Town, to Robert T. Berry, Martinsburg, informing him that they have arrived safely in Charles Town, and that the children are well.
- Letter, 31 January 1864, from T. P. Bell, Company C, 5th Virginia Infantry, Camp Randolph to an unidentified recipient concerning camp life.
- Letter, 12 March no year, from Lizzie Faulkner, Washington D.C., to [Robert T.?] Berry sending a photograph of herself.
- Letter, 7 May no year, from Mr. and Mrs. Henry Berry, Shepherdstown, (West) Virginia, to Mr. and Mrs. Berry, stating that they would be happy to see them 14 May.
- Letter, no date, from an unknown correspondent to Mildred W. Berry, Alexandria, sending news.
- Letter, 14 October no year, from Polly N. Hanna, Baltimore, Maryland, to Eliza M. Frame, Charles Town, concerning a piano and Eliza's mother.
- Letter, 18 December no year, from Katherine [Berry, later Bedinger], Fredericksburg, to Robert T. Berry, Princeton, New Jersey, sending family and social news.
- Letter, no date, from Katherine H. Bedinger, Fredericksburg, to Robert T. Berry, Georgetown, concerning their brother Alexander Berry.
- Ticket, no date, to Reverend Mr. and Mrs. Berry to see West's painting.
- Letter, no date, from Lizzie Faulkner to Mr. Berry, regretting to hear that he is sick and sending a bottle of brandy and sugar as medicine
- Letter, no date, from Robert T. Berry, Front Royal, Virginia, to Anne F. Berry, Charles Town, concerning his trip and personal and social news.
- Letter, no date, from E. L. G. to Anne F. Berry, Martinsburg, asking why Margret [sic] has not come up.
- Letter, no date, from Eliza M. Griggs to Anne F. Berry, Georgetown, sending family and social news.
- Notes, no date, concerning eating and religious thoughts.